Yanzhi (Aaron) Dou

3000 Richmond Lane Apartment D Blacksburg, VA 24060 540-557-7783 yzdou@vt.edu ♠ in yzdou.info

Background Summary More than 4 years research experience in building/securing computer networks and systems. Self-motivated researcher with excellent analytical and programming skills. Strong work ethics, good interpersonal skills, can work both independently and as a team player.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. candidate, Computer Engineering, Virginia Tech, USA Sep 2013 – Sep 2017 - Expected to get degree within 4 years; Cumulative GPA: 3.94/4.00

M.S., Computer Engineering, Virginia Tech, USA

Aug 2013 – Dec 2016

B.E., Electrical Engineering, Tsinghua University, China Aug 2009 – June 2013

Academic Talent Program, Tsinghua University, China Aug 2009 – June 2011

TECHNICAL SKILLS Programming: Python(Proficient), Matlab (Proficient), C/C++, JAVA

Platforms: GNU Radio, USRP, Linux, Windows

Professional Experience

Research Assistant at Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA

Aug 2013-present

- Built privacy-preserving Dynamic Spectrum Access system based on secure multiparty computation. Won \$750k funding from NSF together with my advisor. Participated in INFOCOM Business Innovation Challenge Panel.
- Built malware detection system for Cognitive Radio using machine learning techniques.

Research Assistant at **Tsinghua University**, Beijing

Oct 2012–Aug 2013

- Participated in 973 China National Key Research project. Proposed a low-complexity joint resources sharing model for Cognitive Radio networks based on game theory. Published one journal paper as undergraduate.

Intern at **Tongfang Health Technology**, Beijing

June 2012-Sep 2012

- Improved UI of WINCE-driven body composition analyzers.

Funding

Preserving User Privacy in Server-driven Dynamic Spectrum Access System.

- National Science Foundation (NSF), Grant CNS-1547366, \$750k
- Investigators: Yaling Yang and Yanzhi Dou (VT); Kui Ren (SUNY, Buffalo)

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

<u>Yanzhi Dou</u>, He Li, Kexiong (Curtis) Zeng, Jinshan Liu, Yaling Yang, Bo Gao and Kui Ren. "Preserving Incumbent Users' Privacy in Exclusion-Zone-Based Spectrum Access Systems.", *IEEE International Conference on Distributed Systems (ICDCS)* 2017.

<u>Yanzhi Dou</u>, Kexiong (Curtis) Zeng, He Li, Yaling Yang, Bo Gao, Chaowen Guan, Kui Ren, and Shaoqian Li. "P2-SAS: Preserving Users' Privacy in Centralized Dynamic

Spectrum Access Systems.", ACM International Symposium on Mobile Ad Hoc Networking and Computing (MobiHoc) 2016. (Top 18%)

Yanzhi Dou, Kexiong (Curtis) Zeng, Yaling Yang and Danfeng Yao. "MadeCR: Correlation-based Malware Detection for Cognitive Radio", *IEEE Conference on Computer Communications (INFOCOM)* 2015. (Top 19%).

<u>Yanzhi Dou</u>, Kexiong (Curtis) Zeng, He Li, Yaling Yang, Bo Gao, Kui Ren, and Shaoqian Li. "P2-SAS: Privacy-Preserving Centralized Dynamic Spectrum Access System.", *IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications* (*JSAC*) 2016.

<u>Yanzhi Dou</u>, Bo Bai, Manxi Wang, Wei Chen, Zhigang Cao. "A Mechanism for Low-Complexity Joint Resources Sharing Based on Game Theory in Cognitive Radio Networks", *Journal of Electronics and Information Technology (JEIT)* 2015.

Honors & Awards

Outstanding student award from CESCA	2017
Selected participant in the ACM Student Research Competition (SRC)	2016
Student Travel Grant from MobiCom'16, MobiHoc'16, ICDCS'16.	2016
Student Travel Grant from MobiCom'15, INFOCOM'15.	2015
Outstanding research prize in Student Research Training (SRT).	2013
Progress scholarship.	2012